Finding Aid for the Recordings of Creative Associates Recitals, 1964-1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Reel to reel tapes, 1964-1980, I.; Reel 1-Reel 172
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 112, May 11, 1978, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 14, Reel 156)
    Performers: Gary Hatt, clarinet; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Michael Peebles, violoncello; Krzysztof Knittel, piano
    Cassette backup: CA 623
    Work number: ubmu0063_156_03
    Lacy, Steve
    Six Songs: The Breath, Case Paucer Is, Carroll, Art, Cenis Ceres
    Performers: Carol Plantamura, soprano; Robert Dick, Keith Underwood, flutes (piccolo); Michael Peebles, violoncello; Gregory Ketchum, percussion
    Duration: 23:01
    Cassette backup: CA 624
    Note: Comprised of 5 individual songs
    Work number: ubmu0063_156_04
    Hendrix, Jimi
    Jimi Hendrix Medley, arranged
    Performers: Robert Dick and Keith Underwood, amplified flutes
    Duration: 23:46
    Cassette backup: CA 625
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 113, September 13, 1978, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 14, Reel 157)
    Work number: ubmu0063_157_01
    Parry, John
    Sonata in D Major
    Performers: Mario Falcao, harp
    Duration: 10:30
    Cassette backup: CA 626
    Work number: ubmu0063_157_02
    Viotti, Giovanni Battista
    Sonata in B-flat major
    Duration: 18:14
    Cassette backup: CA 627
    Work number: ubmu0063_157_03
    Willey, James Henry
    Fantasy (1977)
    Duration: 6:38
    Cassette backup: CA 628
    Work number: ubmu0063_157_04
    Holliger, Heinz
    Sequenzen uber Johannes 1, 32
    Duration: 4:07
    Cassette backup: CA 629
    Work number: ubmu0063_157_05
    Suite, harp, op. 83
    Duration: 13:56
    Cassette backup: CA 630
    Work number: ubmu0063_157_06
    Caplet, Andre
    Divertissements pour la harpe
    Duration: 11:27
    Cassette backup: CA 631
    Work number: ubmu0063_157_07
    Salzedo, Carlos
    Song in the Night
    Cassette backup: CA 632
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 114, October 5, 1978, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 14, Reel 158)
    Work number: ubmu0063_158_01
    Shun-San (1969)
    Duration: 12:26
    Cassette backup: CA 633
    Work number: ubmu0063_158_02
    Sonata, viola, violoncello
    Performers: Weronika Knittel, violin; Ken Ishii, violoncello
    Duration: 21:28
    Cassette backup: CA 634
    Work number: ubmu0063_158_03
    Formants I: Les Gestes (1965)
    Duration: 10:40
    Cassette backup: CA 634a
    Note: Not transferred to cassette
    Work number: ubmu0063_158_04
    Why Patterns? (1978)
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Jan Williams, glockenspiel; Morton Feldman, piano
    Duration: 34:30
    Cassette backup: CA 635
    Note: Premiere performance
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 115, November 29, 1978, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 14, Reel 159)
    Work number: ubmu0063_159_01
    Sonata, violin alone, op. 115
    Duration: 15:35
    Cassette backup: CA 636
    Work number: ubmu0063_159_02
    Sonata, violin alone, op. 27, no. 4
    Duration: 12:16
    Cassette backup: CA 637
    Work number: ubmu0063_159_03
    Sonata, violin alone
    Duration: 34:15
    Cassette backup: CA 638
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 116, December 15, 1978, 3 10-inch reels; ½-track stereo, 7.5 and 15 ips (Box 14-15, Reel 160-162)
    Work number: ubmu0063_160_01
    Niblock, Phill
    Quartet 261.63 Plus and Minus
    Performers: Eberhard Blum, flute; Weronika Knittel, violin; Diane Williams, viola; Ken Ishii, violoncello
    Duration: 23:03
    Cassette backup: CA 639
    Work number: ubmu0063_161_01
    Winterbloom (1978)
    Duration: 18:12
    Cassette backup: CA 640
    Work number: ubmu0063_161_02
    Timps in E (1978)
    Duration: 23:40
    Cassette backup: CA 641
    Work number: ubmu0063_162_01
    Long Distance for Cello (1975)
    Performers: Ken Ishii, violoncello; David Gibson, violoncello on tape
    Duration: 19:59
    Cassette backup: CA 642
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 117, February 22, 1979, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 163)
    Work number: ubmu0063_163_01
    Parisonatina Al'Dodecafonia
    Performers: Ken Ishii, violoncello; Claudia Hoca, piano
    Duration: 11:40
    Cassette backup: CA 643
    Work number: ubmu0063_163_02
    Sonata, violoncello, piano (1948)
    Duration: 24:37
    Cassette backup: CA 644
    Work number: ubmu0063_163_03
    Suite, violoncello alone, no. 3, BWV 1009, C major
    Performers: Ken Ishii, violoncello
    Duration: 21:52
    Cassette backup: CA 645
    Work number: ubmu0063_163_04
    Sonata, violoncello, piano, op. 5, no. 2, G major
    Duration: 27:58
    Cassette backup: CA 646
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 118, March 2, 1979, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 164)
    Work number: ubmu0063_164_01
    Lillian Brook (1978)
    Performers: Michael Pugliese, vibraphone
    Duration: 33:46
    Cassette backup: CA 648
    Work number: ubmu0063_164_02
    Johns Brook (1978)
    Duration: 18:03
    Cassette backup: CA 649
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 119, March 7, 1979, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 165)
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_01
    Sonata, flute alone, BWV 1013, A Minor
    Duration: 4:36
    Cassette backup: CA 650
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_02
    Duration: 6:39
    Cassette backup: CA 651
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_03
    Jolas, Betsy
    Episode (1964)
    Cassette backup: CA 652
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_04
    Precipitation Suite (1969)
    Duration: 13:29
    Cassette backup: CA 653
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_05
    Golden Rain (1979)
    Duration: 8:29
    Cassette backup: CA 654
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_06
    Thimmig, Leslie
    Extensions III (1972)
    Cassette backup: CA 655
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_07
    Raudra (1976)
    Cassette backup: CA 656
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_08
    Bugs in Branches (1978)
    Duration: 4:20
    Cassette backup: CA 657
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_09
    Dolphy, Eric
    Gazzelloni ©. 1960)
    Cassette backup: CA 658
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_10
    Andersen, Joachim
    Op. 15, no. 3, "Con Garbo"
    Duration: 2:34
    Cassette backup: CA 659
    Work number: ubmu0063_165_11
    Cassette backup: CA 660
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 120, April 20, 1979, 1 7-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 2, Reel 166)
    Work number: ubmu0063_166_01
    Formants I - Les Gestes (1965)
    Duration: 10:13
    Cassette backup: CA 661
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 121, April 28, 1979, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 167)
    Work number: ubmu0063_167_01
    Stravinsky, Igor
    Duo Concertant for Violin and piano
    Performers: Benjamin Hudson, violin; Charles Wuorinen, piano
    Duration: 18:10
    Cassette backup: CA 666
    Work number: ubmu0063_167_02
    Wuorinen, Charles
    Duo for Violin and piano (1966-67)
    Duration: 16:46
    Cassette backup: CA 667
    Work number: ubmu0063_167_03
    Piece for Violin and piano (1950)
    Duration: 2:04
    Cassette backup: CA 668
    Work number: ubmu0063_167_04
    Extensions I for Violin and piano (1951)
    Duration: 7:05
    Cassette backup: CA 669
    Work number: ubmu0063_167_05
    Vertical Thoughts II for Violin and piano (1963)
    Duration: 4:23
    Cassette backup: CA 670
    Work number: ubmu0063_167_06
    Spring of Chosroes (1977)
    Duration: 17:10
    Cassette backup: CA 671
    Work number: ubmu0063_167_07
    Pastorale (1933)
    Duration: 4:24
    Cassette backup: CA 672
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 122, September 16, 1979, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 168)
    Work number: ubmu0063_168_01
    Hellerman, William
    Long Island Sound (1974)
    Performers: Robert Dick, flute; Edward Yadzinski, bass clarinet; Weronika Knittel, violin; Joanne Lowe, viola
    Duration: 23:09
    Cassette backup: CA 674
    Work number: ubmu0063_168_02
    Local Exits (1976)
    Performers: Edward Folger, Bruce Penner, vibraphone
    Duration: 35:24
    Cassette backup: CA 675
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 123, September 28, 1979, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips; Note: marking on container indicates this is Reel 2 for the concert but the tape appears to hold all 7 works on the program (Box 15, Reel 169)
    Work number: ubmu0063_169_01
    Density 21.5 (1936)
    Cassette backup: CA 676
    Work number: ubmu0063_169_02
    Desolation (1978)
    Cassette backup: CA 677
    Work number: ubmu0063_169_03
    Di Pietro, Rocco
    Non So Nuotari (1977)
    Performers: Rocco Di Pietro, piano; tape realized by the composer
    Duration: 8:01
    Cassette backup: CA 678
    Work number: ubmu0063_169_04
    Franco's Room (1975)
    Duration: 10:31
    Cassette backup: CA 679
    Work number: ubmu0063_169_05
    Density 21.5 (1946)
    Cassette backup: CA 680
    Work number: ubmu0063_169_06
    Hyxos (1961)
    Duration: 11:43
    Cassette backup: CA 681
    Work number: ubmu0063_169_07
    Aria per piano (1978)
    Performers: Rocco Di Pietro, piano
    Duration: 19:09
    Cassette backup: CA 682
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 124, October 19, 1979, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 170)
    Work number: ubmu0063_170_01
    Teitelbaum, Richard
    Blends
    Performers: Robert Dick, flute; Richard Teitelbaum, electronics
    Duration: 21:43
    Cassette backup: CA 683
    Work number: ubmu0063_170_02
    39*S
    Duration: 8:17
    Cassette backup: CA 684
    Work number: ubmu0063_170_03
    Idealist
    Duration: 6:04
    Cassette backup: CA 685
    Work number: ubmu0063_170_04
    Force
    Duration: 8:42
    Cassette backup: CA 686
    Work number: ubmu0063_170_05
    Shrine
    Duration: 25:55
    Cassette backup: CA 687
    Work number: ubmu0063_170_06
    Gazzelloni
    Cassette backup: CA 688
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 125, February 28, 1980, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 171)
    Work number: ubmu0063_171_01
    Borup-Jorgensen, Axel
    Summer Intermezzi (1971)
    Performers: Erik Skjoldan, piano
    Duration: 11:16
    Cassette backup: CA 689
    Work number: ubmu0063_171_02
    Formant 2-Trope (1961)
    Cassette backup: CA 690
    Work number: ubmu0063_171_03
    Sequenza IV (1966)
    Duration: 10:42
    Cassette backup: CA 691
    Work number: ubmu0063_171_04
    Performers: Erik Skjoldan, piano; tape realized by Erik Skjoldan
    Cassette backup: CA 692
    Work number: ubmu0063_171_05
    Ligeti, Gyorgy
    Trois Bagatelles (1961)
    Cassette backup: CA 693
    Work number: ubmu0063_171_06
    Pour Clavier (1961)
    Duration: 25:05
    Cassette backup: CA 694
  - Creative Associates Recitals no. 126, March 27, 1980, 1 10-inch reel; ½-track stereo, 7.5 ips (Box 15, Reel 172)
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_01
    Brouillards
    Performers: Aki Takahashi, piano
    Cassette backup: CA 695
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_02
    Bruyares
    Duration: 3:05
    Cassette backup: CA 696
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_03
    General Lavine-eccentric
    Duration: 2:50
    Cassette backup: CA 697
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_04
    La terrasse des audiences du clair de lune
    Cassette backup: CA 698
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_05
    Hommage a S. Pickwick Esp. P.P.M.P.C.
    Duration: 3:20
    Cassette backup: CA 699
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_06
    L' Isle Joyeuse
    Cassette backup: CA 700
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_07
    Two piano pieces (1956)
    Duration: 7:29
    Cassette backup: CA 701
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_08
    Sonata, piano, op. 109, E major
    Duration: 20:35
    Cassette backup: CA 702
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_09
    Herma (1961)
    Duration: 7:36
    Cassette backup: CA 703
    Work number: ubmu0063_172_10
    Study, piano, no. 21. Some South Paw Pitching
    Cassette backup: CA 704
- Cassettes, 1964-1980, II.; Box 16-21 (324 audio cassettes)
  Recorded sides are numbered 1-707. The dates above represent the dates of the original recordings, not the dates the cassettes were created as transfers from the reel to reel tapes.
  Box 16 - Cassette sides 1-117
  Box 17 - Cassette sides 118-251
  Box 18 - Cassette sides 252-373
  Box 19 - Cassette sides 374-482
  Box 20 - Cassette sides 483-613
  Box 21 - Cassette sides 614-707
  Arranged in numerical order which also chiefly represents chronological order.
- External hard drive, 2018, III.; 1 external hard drive in Box 21
  Hard drive containing all digital preservation and access files.
  Files contained within folders in concert order.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Department
Subjects
Music--New York (State)--Buffalo; Music--20th century
Genres
Sound recordings
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Evenings for New Music Recordings, 1964-1980
Finding aid for recordings of the major concert series of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts.